<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Integration</title>
<link>https://blog.integrationfest.in/</link>
<atom:link href="https://blog.integrationfest.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>ISI Integration Blog Series</description>
<generator>quarto-1.4.550</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 18:51:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Sauda</title>
  <dc:creator>Shambho Saha</dc:creator>
  <link>https://blog.integrationfest.in/posts/sauda24/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Hey <strong>Integration</strong>! Shambo here.</p>
<p><strong>Integration</strong> started off with a bang on the <em>20th of January</em> with the first edition of the <strong>Prof.&nbsp;Saurabh Ghosh Memorial Lecture Series</strong> in <strong>2024</strong>, honoring the legacy of our very own <strong>Sauda</strong>.</p>
<p><strong><em>Saurabh Ghosh</em></strong>, who was popularly known as <strong>Sauda</strong> among students and staff, worked as a professor in the <em>Human Genetics Unit</em> at <em>ISI</em>. He specialized in <strong>General Epidemiology</strong> and was appointed as the <strong>Dean of Studies</strong> of <em>ISI</em> in <em>2022</em>, just a few weeks before his unfortunate demise on <em>October 3rd, 2022</em>. His sudden death left a profound void in the hearts of his students and colleagues. To commemorate his memory, the <strong>Sauda Memorial</strong> lecture series was initiated in <em>2023</em> as a significant part of <em>Integration</em>.</p>
<p>This time around, we were honored to host <strong>Dr.&nbsp;Viswanathan Mohan</strong>, an internationally acclaimed <em>diabetologist</em> and <em>Chairman</em> of the <strong>Madras Diabetes Research Foundation</strong> and <strong>Dr.&nbsp;Mohan’s Diabetes Specialities Centre</strong>, Chennai, as well as the esteemed <em>Dr.&nbsp;Rajiv Bahl</em>, <em>Director General</em> of the <strong>Indian Council of Medical Research</strong>.</p>
<p>This edition of the lecture series started off with a brilliant introduction to the speakers by <strong>Prof.&nbsp;Partha P. Majumdar</strong>, a close colleague of <em>Sauda</em>, who introduced us to his work with both <strong>MDRF</strong> and the <strong>ICMR</strong>.</p>
<p>The first lecture started with a captivating presentation by <strong>Dr.&nbsp;V. Mohan</strong> on what is known as the “<em>diabetes epidemic in India</em>.” <em>Dr.&nbsp;Mohan</em> spent much of his life carrying out foundational research in the field, crafting solutions, and carrying out people-oriented experiments to get to the root of the issue. He had several success stories to present, including the stories of the <em>ASIAD colony</em> and <em>T Nagar</em> in <em>Chennai</em>, as well as the village of <em>Chunampet</em>, all presented in his unique, witty way of storytelling. (Including a little anecdote about how a philanthropic zamindar got involved with the <strong>ISRO</strong>!) The presentation included a unique blend of statistical work and fieldwork, which enchanted the audience.</p>
<p>The second lecture was also unique in its own right, as <strong>Dr.&nbsp;Rajiv Bahl</strong> set the stage with a series of stories surrounding the most interesting outcome of <strong>medical research—interventions</strong>. This included a discussion of how a seemingly crazy idea by a <em>Colombian doctor</em> running an under-resourced facility changed the way medical professionals work with newborns needing incubators. This technique was called <em>Kangaroo Mother Care</em> since it utilized the body heat of the mothers themselves. <em>Dr.&nbsp;Bahl’s</em> unique expertise on the subject of post-research interventions made the talk engaging.</p>
<p>The session ended with several thought-provoking questions posed by attentive members of the audience, the answers to which were the cherry on top of the lecture series.</p>
<p>As the event concluded, the audience was left wanting for more such lectures in the future as part of the coming editions of <strong>Integration</strong>.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed reading about the event as much as we enjoyed hosting it. Stay tuned for future updates on <strong>Integration 2024</strong>!</p>
<p><strong>Auf wiedersehen!</strong></p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://blog.integrationfest.in/posts/sauda24/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 18:51:01 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
